- 抱歉迟到了-没关系
- Sorry for being late - No, it's okay
你为什么不点东西？
Why didn't you order anything?
不 我没想到你会来所以
No I didn't think you would be coming, so
但是 我还是来了
Yet here I am
不用了，谢谢，我什么都不要，请便吧
No, thank you I don't want anything Please go ahead
- 确定?-是的 当然 请
- Sure? - Yes Sure Please
不好意思
Excuse me
[ Sucheta ]“所以，上次你拒绝和我说话”
[Sucheta] 'So, the last time you refused to talk to me'
什么改变了
'What changed?'
好奇，很好
Curious Good
我对别的事情很好奇
I'm curious about something else
我们正在经历一场经济危机
We were going through an economic crisis
政府变了，首相也变了，一切都变了
Government changed, the prime minister changed Everything changed
但是股票市场保持稳定，现在依然如此
But the stock market remained stable And it still is
你在暗示什么？
What are you trying to insinuate?
每个人都在赚钱
Everyone is making a profit
这是件好事
That's a good thing
每个人？
Everyone?
所以
So
你是说
you mean
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔和他的追随者？
Harshad Mehta and his followers?
在哈尔沙德•巴伊(Harshad Bhai)统治时期，市场变得疯狂
'In Harshad Bhai's reign, the market goes insane'
我能跟你说实话吗？
Can I be honest with you?
我不太喜欢梅塔先生
I'm not a very big fan of Mr Mehta
那你就是个例外
Then you are an exception
因为你们兄弟会的人
Because the people of your fraternity
宣称他是市场上最伟大的学者
have declared him the greatest scholar in the market
[ DT ]“有些人甚至认为他应该当财政部长”
[DT] 'Some even think that he should be the finance minister'
梅塔先生肯定能成为一名部长
Mr Mehta can surely become a minister
他总是发表演说
He is always delivering speeches
但我个人认为他的理论都是垃圾
But I I personally, think his theories are just rubbish
没人在乎你我的想法
Nobody cares what you and I think
现在，资金正在流入市场
Right now, money is flowing into the market
每个人都在这条河里游泳
and everyone is taking a dip in this river
但是没有人关心这条河的源头在哪里
But no one cares where the source of this river is
这些钱是从哪里来的？
Where is all this money coming from?
你知道，很多人认为这是脏钱？
You know, lots of people think it's the underworld?
毫无根据的理论
Baseless theories
那么，这些资金来自哪里呢？
So, where are the funds coming from?
哈沙德不需要黑社会
Harshad doesn't need
或政党资助他
the underworld or political parties to fund him
政府在他的掌控之中
He has the government in his pocket
他打了一个电话，他在德里的朋友
He makes one phone call, and his friends in Delhi
指示所有政府机构
instruct all government institutions
为他提供所有他想要的资金
to provide him with all the funds he wants
你有什么证据吗？
Do you have any proof for this?
没有，但我很确定
No But I know it for sure
上次我试着联系你
Last time, I tried to reach out to you
因为我正在写一篇关于货币市场违规现象的报道
because I was doing a story on the irregularities in the money market
但你似乎只对哈尔沙德 · 梅塔感兴趣
But you seem to be interested only in Harshad Mehta
是的
Yes
因为在货币市场也是，一切都乱套了
Because in money market also, everything is going haywire
所有的金融机构和银行都在哈沙德的控制之下
All the financial institutions and banks are under Harshad's control
他垄断了所有的证券，并在市场中占据了一席之地
He is cornering all the securities and taking positions in the market
现在
Right now
其他的都不重要
nothing else matters
不是你的优点，不是你的技能，什么都不是
Not your merit, not your skill Nothing
唯一重要的是
The only thing that matters is
你能贿赂这些银行官员多少钱
how much you can grease the palms of these bank officials
因为哈沙德很擅长这个
Because Harshad is very good at it
他这样做了，所以我们也不得不这样做
He does it, so we are also compelled to do it
如果我们不能让银行官员满意
If we don't keep the bank officials happy
甚至都得不到我们所做的小生意
we won't even get the little business that we do
上周，UCO 银行
Last week, UCO Bank
给了哈尔沙德五亿卢比的纯信用贷款
gave Harshad a clean credit of fifty crores
你了解信用贷款吗？
Do you understand clean credit?
不需要任何担保
Without any collateral
你想让我为此写篇报道？
And you want me to do a story on this?
我可以引用你的话吗？
Can I quote you on this?
不可以
No
那就没有报道了
Then there is no story
就像你说的，没人在乎我们的想法
As you said, nobody cares about what we think
如果我要刊登反对哈尔沙德先生的文章
If I have to print anything against Mr Harshad Mehta
那就需要确凿的证据
then I will need solid evidence
我不能对他做任何事
I can't do anything against him
因为我需要这些细节来揭露他的作案手法
because I will need those details to expose his modus operandi
我需要你的帮助
I will need something from you
好吧
Fine
你很快就会得到确凿的证据
You will get your solid evidence soon
在我们进去之前，我想提醒你，我爸爸是个非常守旧的人
Before we enter, I want to warn you that my dad is very old school
一个难对付的家伙
A hard nut to crack
你知道，他的观念非常传统
He is very, like you know, orthodox in his methods
兄弟
Brother
不管老派还是新派
Old school or new school
教学大纲都有一个共同的主题
every syllabus has one subject in common
利润
Profit
这是我最喜欢的科目
And that is my favourite subject
阿姆里克告诉我，在你看来
Amrik was telling me that in your opinion
我们的公司被低估了？
our company is undervalued?
是的，它被低估了
Yes, it is undervalued
这是毫无疑问的
There's no doubt about it
在上个季度，贵司赚了超过2亿卢比的利润
In the last quarter, you earned a profit of more than 20 crores
但是股息支付只有40%
But the dividend payout against it is only 40 percent
每股收益只有727卢比
[Harshad] 'And earning per share is just 727 rupees'
我研究贵公司的财务状况已有一段时间了
I have been studying your company's finances for a while
目前的股价是多少? 22-23？
What is the current value of your share? 22-23?
接近28
It touched 28
差不多
Same thing Same range
到年底你预计股价达到多少？
And where do you intend to go by the year-end?
至少翻一倍
Minimum double
我相信，我可以把你们公司的股价提高到400
I believe, I can take your company's share up to 400
花言巧语，我以前听过
-[scoffs] - Plain rhetoric I've heard this before
我说你低估了公司的价值
See, when I said that you are undervaluing your company
我的意思是
what I meant is
你不应该仅仅根据收入来评价你的公司
that you should not value your company only on the basis of what it earns
告诉我，你们什么时候开始做生意的？
Tell me When did you commence your business?
1972年
那是19年，很长一段时间
That's 19 years Long time
你投入了很多
You've invested a lot
你的激情，你的时间，所有那些不眠之夜
[Harshad] 'Your passion, your time, all those sleepless nights'
介意我站起来吗？
You mind if I get up?
-请便 -谢谢
- Please - Thanks
那么，19年前，你投资了多少钱来建立这个公司？
So, 19 years back, how much money did you invest to build this company?
今天，用同样的金额，是否有可能建立一个类似的公司？
Today, with the same amount, is it possible to build a similar company?
不可能，对吧？
Not possible, right?
那么，要建立一个像 Polo 这样的公司，你现在需要多少钱？
So, to build a company like Polo, how much money would you need today?
这才是你公司的真正价值所在
Now that's the real value of your company
真正的价值
The true value
我称之为重置成本理论
I call it my replacement cost theory
以 ACC 的股票为例
Take the example of ACC shares
股价曾经是300
It was at 300
那今天呢？
And today?
三千
Three thousand
看，在股票市场上，有些人相信命运
Look, in the share market, some people believe in fate
但我只相信价值
but I only believe in value
据我所知
And from what I understand
你公司的价值比你想象的要高得多
the value of your company is much higher than you think
我不确定你的方法是否合法
I'm not sure if your methods are legitimate
在股票市场，一切都是合法的
In the share market, everything is legitimate
我的方法是新的，非传统的
My methods are new, unconventional
所以人们觉得是非法的
so, people find them illegitimate
这对你有什么好处？
What's in it for you?
一部分股权
A part Stakes
多少？
How much?
很大一部分
Sizeable
梅塔先生
Mr Mehta
不久之前
some time back
你控股了马自达
you had acquired Mazda
我白手起家建立了这个公司
I have built this company on my own
我仍然想拥有它
and I still want to own it
你误会了
You are misunderstanding
想要股权并不意味着我想接管你的公司
Wanting a stake, doesn't mean I want to take over your company
我的工作是创造财富
I am in the business of creating wealth
我对卖钢铁不感兴趣
I'm not interested in selling steel
那是你的专长
That's your expertise
我甚至不想要董事会席位
I don't even want a position on your board
我没有看上你的公司
I'm not eyeing your company
- 但我-对它的真正价值感兴趣
- But I'm - Interested in its real value
你懂我
There you are
你就杵在那不说话吗？
Will you just stand there or ask what's on your mind?
你给Polo做出了类似ACC的承诺
The promise you've made to push up Polo shares, like ACC
你有没有为此筹集资金的计划？
Do you have a plan to raise funds for it?
[阿什温]‘或者还是像往常一样，得到尚蒂拉尔 · 梅塔的祝福? ”’
[Ashwin] 'Or as usual, ‘with the blessings of Shantilal Mehta?''
我们会从Polo那里得到一些资金
We will get some funds from Polo itself
辛格先生的儿子也参加了会议
Mr Singh's son was also in the meeting
他是个聪明的孩子，他说，有什么需要，尽管告诉我
He is a smart boy He said, anything you need, let me know
这是他父亲的公司
It's his father's company
在他父亲的统治下，他能许诺什么呢？
How can he promise anything under his father's rule?
或者你脑子里有什么我不知道的东西，像往常一样
Or there's something in your mind that I don't know about, as usual
没问题的
It will be done
我们得到的股份将用作抵押，以获得银行贷款
The shares we get, we'll use as collateral to get a bank loan
我也和共同基金公司谈过，他们正想收购一些股票
I've also spoken to mutual fund companies They are buying some shares
而且，我认识一些想在印度投资的外国公司
And, I know some foreign companies who want to invest in India
但不是通过正规渠道
But not through regular channels
- 剩下的就交给他们了-没关系，哈沙德
- The rest will come from them - That's fine, Harshad
但我们应该知道你所有的策略
But all your strategies should be known to us
除了你以外，我们都没有资金流动的帐户
No one except you has any account of the flow of funds
是时候了
It's time
是时候启动高摩的IPO了
to launch the IPO of Growmore
我告诉过你
I had told you
我想把高摩带到更高的地方
I want to take Growmore so high
我们就不用为了钱到处乱跑了
that we won't have to go Running around for funds
等着瞧吧
Just wait and watch
到今年年底，Sensex指数将会超过2000点
by the end of the year, the sensex will kiss 2000
你看过美林(Merrill Lynch)的资产负债表吗？
Have you seen Merrill Lynch's balance sheet?
你知道他们去年赚了多少钱吗？
Do you know how much profit they made last year?
二百亿卢比
Two thousand crores
我们做了什么
- And what did we make? -[billiard ball clacking]
我们应该与美林(Merrill Lynch)展开直接竞争
We should be in direct competition with Merrill Lynch
现在，我们只关注一件事
Now, the focus is on just one thing
让高摩超过美林
To make Growmore bigger than Merrill Lynch
真的吗？
Really?
这样的话，我想当首相
In that case, I want to be the Prime Minister
“嘿  ”
[Maheshwari] 'Hey'
把钱存起来，买股票
'Save the money You can use them to buy shares'
看他在跳舞
Look at him dancing
- 看看他的动作-是的
- Look at his moves - Yes
让他跳吧
Let him dance
跳舞使他放松
Dancing relaxes him
是的，还能娱乐我们
Yes And entertains us
他还发现了在厕所里撒尿的娱乐
And he finds entertainment peeing in the toilet
市场一下跌，他就跑去撒尿
The moment the market falls, he runs to pee
对
Right
你看到Polo的股价了吗？
Did you see the price of Polo?
五个月内，从70涨到230
In five months, its gone from 70 to 230
哈尔沙德正像打水漂一样往里面投钱
Harshad is pouring money into it like water
现在随时都会有洪水
There will be a flood anytime now
五个月内涨了八倍
800 percent gain in five months
八倍
800 percent
-八倍，马赫什瓦里大哥!-是的
- 800 percent, Maheshwari Bhai! - Yes
这不是玩笑，简直是疯了
It's not a joke, it's f*****g insanity
嘿，别像马努那样咒骂了
Hey, stop cussing like Manu Bhai
算了吧！
Forget it, M**********r!
你有笔吗？
Do you have a pen?
-我给你看，等一下-什么？
- Let me show you, hold on - What?
我画个图给你看
I'll make a chart and show you
一旦下降趋势开始
Once a downward trend starts
是的
Yes
- 一旦我们开始抛售 Polo 的股票-是的
- Once we start selling Polo shares - Yes
马上就会开始下跌
the downward movement will start
是的
Okay
Polo会垮掉，哈沙德也会垮掉
Then Polo will fall and Harshad will break
到时候哈尔沙德会怎样？
How will Harshad break?
即使遇到阻力，我们还有什么好卖的？
Even if it hits a resistance, what have we got to sell?
哈尔沙德几乎把所有与 Polo 有关的股票都装进了腰包
Harshad has stuffed almost all Polo shares up his warm a***
那么，让我们再给他热热身吧
So, let's warm his a*** some more
- 我们把它点着吧-你说得对
- Let's set it on fire - You are absolutely right
- 快点起来-不求你了
- Come on Get up - No, please
- 我们去和阿贾伊谈谈-走吧
- Let's talk to Ajay Bhai - Come on
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
- 不，求你了-来吧
- No, please - Yes
实际上凯迪亚先生说的没错，我们确实有Polo的股份
'Actually Mr Kedia was right We do have Polo shares'
事实上，梅塔先生已经向我们抵押了很多他的股份
In fact, Mr Mehta has pledged a lot of his shares with us
因为他和我们银行的关系很好
since he has an excellent relationship with our bank
得了吧，维尔马先生
Come on, Mr Verma
我在银行的经历教会了我一件事
My experience with banks has taught me one thing
你只对一种人感兴趣
You are interested in only one kind of relationship
就是那个给你钱和利润的人
the one that gives you money and profit
对吧？
Right?
我就直说了
I'll speak directly From one banker to another
你有抵押给你的股份
You have the shares pledged with you
有权利把它借出去
You are well within your rights to lend them
如果你把股票借出去，那么从我们在市场上获得的利润中
If you lend the shares, then from the profit we make in the market
你会的
you will
我是说 Grindlays 也会分一杯羹
I mean, Grindlays will get a share too
嗯
Hmmm
梅塔先生呢？
And Mr Mehta?
如果他知道了怎么办？
What if he gets to know?
先生，股票市场上有数以百万计的股票在流动
Sir, millions of shares move around in the share market
哈萨德怎么会知道？
How will Harshad get to know?
别担心，我会支持你的
Don't worry I've got your back
但时间至关重要
But time is crucial
我们需要尽快完成这件事
And we need to do this quickly
你的“Karamchand”做了所有这些分析？
Your 'Karamchand' has done all this analysis?
- 别叫我的线人“Karamchand”-好的
- Don't call my source 'Karamchand' - Okay
无论如何，在他看来，主要政府机构都在帮助哈萨德
Anyway, in his opinion, major institutions are helping Harshad
- 他在告诉我们怎么做-好吧看这个
And he is telling us how Okay Look at this
就在这一天，UTI 大量买进
This was the day, UTI bought heavily
而在这一天，LIC 被迫收购了
And this was the day, LIC was made to buy
看看这些数量
Look at the volumes
不管什么时候发生这种事
And whenever this has happened
哈沙德持有的股票都会暴涨
Harshad's shares have shot up in value
苏切塔，你不认为你是在推测吗？
Sucheta, don't you think that you are speculating?
你不能写这种只基于推测的东西
And you can't write anything, only on the basis of speculation
是的，但是推测会引导我找到细节，不是吗？
Yes But speculation will lead me to the specifics, won't it?
我相信我们会有收获的
I'm sure we'll get something
好吧，我同意，但我还是不明白
Okay, agreed But I still don't get it
为什么你的线人要分享这些信息？
Why is your 'Karamchand' sharing this information?
他是在吃胡萝卜还是在吊你的胃口？
Is he eating the carrot or dangling it for you?
我不知道
I don't know
他也不是圣人，这是他自己说的
He is no saint either He says it himself
那他为什么要追杀哈沙德？
Why is he after Harshad then?
因为哈沙德把自己描绘成市场之王
Because Harshad portrays himself as the king of the market
除非有人向他敬礼，否则没人有机会
And unless they salute him, no one stands a chance
所以，这是私人恩怨
So, it's personal
这是主观的
It's subjective
我觉得
I think
一个小偷正在揭露一个强盗
a thief is exposing a bandit
而强盗总是要付出代价
And the price is always on the bandit's head
那么，你下一步打算怎么做？
So, what's your next move?
- 我在想我会就此事与印度证券交易所长接触-证券交易所？
- I'm thinking I'll approach the SEBI governor on this - SEBI?
证交所不是执法机构
SEBI is a non-statutory body, Sucheta
这只是个形式
It's only a formality
他们不能规范市场
They can't regulate the market
那里唯一的规则就是经纪人
The only rules there, are the brokers
是的，但他们应该知道这些违规行为
Yes, but they should know about these irregularities
他们一定有办法采取行动
They must have a way to take action
你是个记者
You are a journalist
- 不是激进分子-随便了
- Not an activist - Whatever
先生，如果你仔细看，过去的六个月
Sir, if you look closely, in the last six months
所有的暴涨喝暴跌都是由一个因素造成的
all the highs and lows have been brought on by one single factor
什么因素？
What single factor?
-哈尔沙德·梅塔-哈尔沙德·梅塔？
- Harshad Mehta - Harshad Mehta?
你在说什么？
What are you saying?
在你的图表中
In your graph
很明显这些都是机构投资者
it's clear that these are institutional investors
政府主导的机构
Government-led institutions
尽管如此，你是说
Despite that, you are saying
他们被股票经纪人哈尔沙德·梅塔所控制？
they are controlled by Harshad Mehta, a stockbroker?
你有证据吗？
You have any proof?
- 没有，先生，现在没有-那你有什么？
- No, sir Not at the moment - Then?
先生，我只有我的打字机和线人
Sir, I only have my typewriter and my sources
就是这样
[Sucheta] 'That's it'
先生，我不需要告诉你这个，你是证交所所长
Sir, I don't need to tell you this You are the SEBI governor
如果你想要证据，你可以用你的资源
If you want proof then you have all the means by which
你可以进一步调查
you can take this investigation further
先生，我只是认为我有责任让你注意到这件事
Sir, I just thought that it was my moral responsibility to bring this to your notice
这些 Polo 股票是从哪里进入市场的?
[Harshad] 'From where are all these Polo shares coming into the market?'
谁在出售它们
'Who is selling them?'
从230下降到208
It's fallen from 230 to 208
对
Right
我也是这么想的
That's what I'm thinking
我们已经买了最高限额
We have bought the maximum
先生，您的快递
Sir, a courier
我从市场上买了一些 Polo 的股票，看看是否一样
I called for some Polo shares from the market Check if they are the same
看看这个
[Ashwin] 'Look at this'
上面有我们公司的印章
It has our company's stamp on it
有个白痴在结算时把我们的股票卖给了我们
Some idiot has sold us our shares at the time of settlement
Grindlays!
我们应该抓住这个把柄
[Ashwin] 'Let's catch Grindlays by the balls'
告诉他们留着他们的钱归还我们的股份
tell them to keep their money and return our shares
不
No
不是Grindlays干的，这是熊队的游戏
This is not Grindlays It's the bears' game
如果我们需要解决什么人，那就是熊
If there's someone we need to tackle, it's the bears
什么意思？
Meaning?
如果我们和 Grindlays 谈
If we talk to Grindlays
熊会立刻得到我们的信息
the bears will immediately get information, that we know
现在不是防御的时候，而是进攻的时候
This isn't the time to defend but to attack
在接下来的两个月里，让那些看空者尽可能多地抛售股票吧
Let those bears hammer as many shares as they want, for the next two months
他们应该会觉得我们没有资金了
They should feel we are out of funds
然后，在适当的时候，我再把股价抬上去
Then, at the right time, I'll shove a stick so high up
让那些该死的熊失去方向感
that the bloody bears' balls will lose their bearings
你没问那个问题？
You didn't ask the question?
什么问题？
What question?
上次的问题
The usual
这些资金将从哪里来
‘Where will the funds come from?'
我知道你能应付
I know you will manage
你不用告诉我
and you won't even tell me
但是在你做任何事情之前都要三思，不要冲动
But think before you do anything Don't be impulsive
西塔拉曼先生
Mr Sitaraman
请坐
Have a seat
你好吗? 一切都好吗？
How are you? All well?
咖啡？
Coffee?
不用，先生，我刚喝了咖啡
No, sir I just had coffee
真的吗？
Really?
你带来了价值五十亿卢比的支票
You have brought cheques worth 500 crores
对吧？
You have, haven't you?
那为什么不愿意喝100卢比的咖啡呢？
Then why shy away from a 100 rupee coffee? Huh?
兄弟
Brother
给他一杯浓咖啡，我要茶
A strong coffee for sir, and tea for me
49.9亿，先生
499, Sir
- 都签好了-太好了
- All signed - Great
先生
Sir
- 先生-什么事？
- Sir - Yes?
我什么时候能拿到SGL？
When will I get SGL for it, sir?
没有的
Never
谁还在用SGL？
Who gives SGL these days?
我给你BRs，好吗？
I'll give you BRs Okay?
别这么紧张，兄弟，你已经把它交给我了
Don't get so tense, brother You've handed it to me now
风险已经转移到我身上了，不是吗？
Isn't this tension, that I'm taking from you?
而且，我也不打算把它保留太久
And, I don't intend to keep it for long
就这几天而已
It's only a matter of a few days
你看，SGL 我的意思是，一旦我得到 BRs
You see, Sir, the SGL I mean once I get the BRs
我需要在账本上做记录
I need to make entries in the books
再过几天
[Sitaraman] 'Then after a few days'
我需要统计 PDO 的账目
I need to tally the books in PDO
所有这些都需要几天时间，所以
All this takes a few days So
亲爱的，你担心得太多了
Darling, you worry too much
这是我与 SBI 的第一笔交易吗？
Is this my first deal with SBI?
先生，这次是一大笔钱
Sir, this time, it's a big amount
还有印度储备银行的指导方针，先生
And the RBI guidelines, sir
在你的脑海里，你已经把这点钱想了珠穆朗玛峰
You have turned this tiny amount to Mount Everest in your mind
“对我来说，每一笔钱都很少”
[Harshad] 'For me, every amount is small'
过几天你就能拿到钱，到时候你就可以入账了
You'll get the money in a few days You can do the entry then
听着，如果金额很大
Look, if the amount is big
利润也会很大，对吧？
the profit should be big too, right?
我会以你妻子的名义买一些股票
I'll buy a few shares in your wife's name
希望你不介意
I hope that's okay
先生，在审计之后
Sir, after the audit
我们给这些银行下了严格的指示
we gave strict instructions to these banks
严格遵守印度储备银行的准则
to strictly follow the RBI guidelines
但其中一些银行一直在藐视规定
But some of these banks have been flouting rules
他们不把我们当回事
They are not taking us seriously
几根搅屎棍，先生
A few rotten apples, sir
主席先生，请看一下 SBI 的报告
Sir, please take a look at SBI's report
有什么特别的吗？
Anything specific?
先生，我不知道他们这些天是怎么做证券交易的？
Sir, I'm not sure how they are doing their securities transactions these days?
[穆克吉]“我的意思是，他们似乎确实保留了记录，但是  ”
[Mukherjee] 'I mean, it seems they do maintain records but'
只会让大家感到困惑
'only to confuse everybody'
当然，除了那些记录的人
Of course, excepting those who are creating it
先生，为了监控这些交易我们应该建立
Sir, to monitor these transactions we should create
-一个特别部门-不不
- a special department in SBI - No No, Mukherjee
我们不能这么做
We can't do that
印度国家银行正在努力为我们的外汇储备引导海外资金
The SBI is working hard to channelize funds from abroad for our foreign exchange reserves
我们现在不能进行任何公开调查
We can't do any open investigation now
你应该知道
You should know this
不管怎样，我明白你的意思了
Anyway, I get your point
我会仔细研究你的报告
I'll study your report thoroughly and
我会直接和印度国家银行主席谈的，好吗？
I'll talk to the SBI chairman directly Okay?
我带着所有的成果去找他
I went with all my homework
给他看了所有的数字图表，所有的东西
I showed him all the numbers Graphs, charts, everything
但是他还没有准备好去相信它
But he's just not ready to believe it
他一心想要证据
All he wanted was proof
如果没有证据，什么都不会做
'If we don't get proof, we won't do anything'
这并没有错，你知道
And that's not wrong, you know
每个人都习惯了做自己职责范围内的事
Everyone has gotten used to working within boundaries
六个月前我就预测到了这种模式
I predicted this whole pattern six months back
如果你还记得
And if you remember
我预言没有确凿的证据，就不会有新闻
I predicted that without solid evidence, we will not have a story
没有证据，没有证人，我们什么也做不了
Without proof or a witness, we can't do anything
会有的，耐心点
You will get someone Just be patient
我很有耐心，但我很沮丧
I am patient but I'm frustrated
我知道
I know
如果这种情况继续下去，证交所可能会更名为哈交所
If this continues, BSE will have to change to HSE
哈尔沙德证券交易所
Harshad Stock Exchange
小心！
-[honks] - Watch out!
谢天谢地，还好我刚换了轮胎
Thank God, I just replaced the tyres
哈尔沙德
Harshad
布尚说我们正在从世界各地购买 Polo 的股票？
Bhushan says we are buying Polo shares from everywhere?
这些事到办公室去谈
Let's talk calmly in the office
你又动用了银行资金？
Are you using banking funds?
坐
Sit
从哪来的钱？
From where?
- 坐下-多少钱？
- Sit down - How much?
这是我们第一次这么做吗？
Is this the first time we are doing it? Huh?
钱是SBI的
It's from SBI
不到50亿卢比，预计还有10亿卢比
A little less than 500 crores, and another 100 is expected
哪家银行给了你这么大一笔存款？
And which bank has given you BRs for such a huge amount?
我已经告诉他们钱是来自旁遮普国家银行
I've told them securities will come from PNB
你告诉他们了？
You've told them?
哈沙德
Harshad
你疯了吗，哈沙德？
Are you out of your mind, Harshad?
没有 BRs 也没有证券
Without BRs or securities
- 你从 SBI 那里拿了50亿? !-就几天而已
- you took 500 Crores from SBI?! - It's only for a few days
我会在他们结账前还给他们
I'll repay them before they close their books
你可以问我的
You could've asked
我该问谁呢？
Whom would I ask? Huh?
我们会被困住
We will get trapped
在一个地方拼命榨取，你会跌落谷底的，哈沙德
In trying to hustle in one place, you'll break at a hundred more, Harshad
- 别这么消极-消极？
- Stop being so negative - Negative?
我不能做圣人的生意，明白吗？
I can't do business playing a saint Got it?
如果我听了你的话，我们早就关门大吉了，就像爸爸一样
Had I listened to you, we would've already shut down our business, just like Pappa
有必要在家里谈这个吗？
Is it necessary to talk about this at home?
“给我拿点茶来”
[Harshad] 'Get me some tea'
好球，哈沙德
Well done, Harshad
你根本都不懂板球
You aren't even playing
你为什么来？
Why did you come?
我必须来，我是他的搭档
I have to I'm his partner
- 搭档?-是的，怎么了？
- Partner? - Yes, why?
什么搭档？
What partner?
你在文件上签字了吗？
Have you signed the papers?
还是名义上的合伙人？
or partner just in name?
你喝你的茶，好吗？
You drink your tea Okay?
我一会回来，别烦我
I'll be back Don't drink my blood!
你是打保龄球的吗，这样太过分了
Bowl properly It's going out of line
哥们，你没看到你扔的球离地多高吗? 这么高
Buddy, can't you see that it's a wide? Such a wide wide
哈沙德，你要一边做裁判一边打球吗？
Harshad Bhai, will you do both, batting and umpiring?
别斗嘴，否则我也要打保龄球了
Don't bicker or I'll have to bowl too
快点，比赛快结束了，去打保龄球吧
Come on The game is almost over Go bowl
过来，哈沙德，过来
'C'mon, Harshad Bhai, c'mon!'
接球
'Catch it!'
小心，他会扔出一个快球
Be careful He will throw a fast one
干得好，哈沙德
Well done, Harshad
你打得很好，很棒的一击
You played so well You played some great strokes
你为什么从来不玩？
Why don't you ever play?
你疯了吗? 如果我受伤了怎么办？
Are you crazy? What if I get hurt?
不是每个人都像你一样
Not everyone has b***s like you
胆小鬼
Coward
把你的勇气藏在两腿之间是不会有任何结果的
Hiding your courage between your legs won't get you anywhere
你得把勇气挂在胸前
You have to pin it on your chest
你的成语和谚语用完了吗？
Are you done with your idioms and proverbs?
我们现在可以谈生意了吗？
Can we talk business now?
星期天有什么生意？
What business on a Sunday?
市场上每个人都在谈论
Everyone is talking in the market
你的合伙人必须知道
Your partner has to listen to it
谁跟阿什温说了什么吗？
Who said anything to Ashwin Bhai?
嘿
Hey
我说的合伙人是我自己
I'm talking about myself
继续，你听到了什么？
Go on now What did you hear?
Polo
大家都说你在操纵价格
Everyone is saying that you are rigging the price
他们要求进行调查
They are asking for an inquiry
谁是‘每个人’ ？
Who is ‘everyone'?
市场上所有的大玩家
All the big players in the market
马努的军队
Manu Bhai's troops
整个熊队
The entire bear gang
如果这还不够的话，还有PMS也是如此
And if that wasn't enough, the PMS investors too
该死
Bloody hell
我已经把他们的投资翻了一番
I have doubled all their investments
熊队能做到吗？
Can the bear gang do that?
多亏了我，每个人的钱包都装满了
Thanks to me, everyone has filled their vaults
现在他们却开始玷污我的名声！
And now they are tarnishing my name M**********rs!
是的，这关系到你的名誉，明白吗？
Yes It's your reputation at stake Got it?
每个人都突然变得勇敢起来
Everyone has suddenly become brave
来，吃个咖喱角
Here Have a Samosa
拿着这个
Hold this
你吃咖喱角
You eat the Samosa
设计是你的专长，我不懂
Designing is your department I won't understand it
对我来说，信息更重要
For me, the message is more important
听着，我想在市场上澄清我对Polo的立场
Look, I want to clear my position on Polo in the market
我为我的投资者赚了很多钱
I have earned a lot of money for my investors
比我承诺的要多得多
A lot more than what I promised
我想让人们知道这一点
I want the people to know this
你看，我在工作
You see I'm working
让这个国家的人民更加繁荣
towards making the people of this country more prosperous
而且，高摩正以其敏锐的商业头脑和诚信的品牌打入市场
And Growmore is playing the market with business acumen and honesty
所以，诚信是关键词
So, honesty is the key word
我想直接对公众发表演讲
And I want to speak to the public directly
我想告诉他们
I want to reach them
那么，应该怎么做？
So, what do they call it?
新闻稿
Press note
这么说吧，这是一个广告形式的新闻
Let’s say, it's a press note turned into an advertisement
我们可以用你的照片吗？
Can we use your face?
我的意思是，我们可以把你的照片放到我们的报道中吗？
I mean, can we put your face in our campaigns?
我又不是阿米塔布·巴沙坎，你却想用我的照片
I am no Amitabh Bachchan, that you want to use my face
先生，公众是这么认为的
Sir, that's what the public thinks
你是这个市场的阿米塔布·巴沙坎
that you are the Amitabh Bachchan of this market
[拉塔]“先生，人们是在质疑你，不是在质疑高摩资本”
[Lata] 'Sir, people are questioning you, not Growmore'
我们需要你的脸，因为你就是那张脸
And we want your face because you are the face
好吧，继续
Okay Go ahead
让广告看起来像报纸上的文章
Make the ad look like a newspaper article
标题应该是
And the headline should be
哈尔沙德·梅塔是个清白的人
Harshad Mehta is a clean man
[拉塔]“这太直接了”
[Lata] 'That is too direct'
事实上，没人会在乎
Nobody cares, actually
没错，没人在乎
That's true Nobody cares
交给他们好了，报纸会刊登这样一个标题：
In fact, left to them, the newspapers will print a headline
哈尔沙德·梅塔是个骗子
Harshad Mehta is a liar
你看这个
Read
我从一开始就知道
I knew it from the start
你是个骗子
that you are a liar
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔是个骗子
Harshad Mehta is a liar
很好，现在报纸上都登了
Good It's even out in the paper now
我对你撒了什么谎？
What lie did I tell you?
真要说吗？
Really?
如果我全都列出来，清单一定比证交所的还长
If I start making a list, even my list will be included in the BSE listing
你答应我去美国，然而实际上连阿姆雷利（印度城市）都没去过
You promised America and didn't even take me to Amreli
但是我们去了欧洲，不是吗？
But we went to Europe, didn't we?
假期来了，我们也要去美国
And let the vacations come, we'll go to America too
如果我们要去的话，现在就要开始计划
If we have to go, we need to start planning now
否则就别去了
Or else, forget about it
所以这次你来制定计划，剩下的我来处理
So this time, you make the plan I'll manage the rest
你确定？
Sure?
- 当然-以我发誓
- Sure - Swear on me
首先，给我捏捏脚
First, massage my legs
如果你不带我去
If it doesn't happen
我会在孟买到处张贴标语
I will put banners all over Bombay
哈尔沙德・梅塔是个骗子，你等着瞧吧
that Harshad Mehta is a liar Just you wait
你看这个了吗？
Did you read it?
“哈尔沙德 · 梅塔是个骗子”
"Harshad Mehta is a liar"
谁会在报纸上刊登这样的东西？
Who gets something like this printed in the newspaper?
是不是有点失控了？
Isn't it getting out of hand?
你看完了吗？
Did you read the full ad?
标题只是为了吸引注意力
The first line is only to grab attention
你看，下面写着哈尔沙德·梅塔是个骗子
Look, it says below, that Harshad Mehta is a liar
因为他为投资者赚取的利润比他承诺的要多得多
because he earned much bigger profits for his investors than he promised
阿什温
Ashwin Bhai
哈尔沙德的这种勇气是从哪里来的？
Where does Harshad get this courage from?
非但没有在市场上澄清自己的立场
Instead of addressing the market and clearing his position
反而在孟买到处张贴海报和宣传画
he has stuck himself on posters and cut-outs all over Bombay
历史开启了新的篇章
A new chapter has been added to history
叫做哈尔沙德 · 梅塔
called Harshad Mehta
现在我不只想要跑步，而是想起飞
Now I don't just want to run, it's the time to leap
我知道阿什温不会理解的
I know Ashwin Bhai won't understand this
但是为什么你不能理解这些呢？
But why can't your brain process this?
市场上的人不能做营销吗？
Can't a person from the market do marketing?
嗯？
Hmm?
看看这张脸
Look at this face
仔细看
Look carefully
它的面值就是我们的净资产
Its face value is our net worth
你想当英雄？
You want to be a hero?
你知道印度最大的制造业是什么吗？
Do you know what India manufactures the most?
- 水泥钢铁-英雄和神明
- Cement, steel - Heroes and gods
今天的平民可以成为明天的英雄
Today's common man can be tomorrow's hero
今天的英雄可以成为明天的上帝
Today's hero can be tomorrow's God
板球运动员，政客，电影明星 他们都这么做
Cricketers, politicians, film stars they all do this
事实上，我们印度人喜欢创造英雄
Actually, we Indians love creating heroes
如果人们觉得哈尔沙德 · 梅塔能给他们一个更光明的未来
If people feel Harshad Mehta can give them a brighter future
有什么问题吗？
what's wrong with that?
越多的人拥护我们，我们就能更多地推动市场
More the people that move towards us, the more we can move the market
听着，我不想去市场做演讲
Look, I don't want to go to the market and give a speech
我想依靠人们的信任
I want to rely on people's trust
这正是我想说的
That's what I'm saying
不要玩弄人们的信任
Don't play with people's trust
[ Sucheta ]“这则广告对他产生了奇妙的效果”
[Sucheta] ‘The ad did wonders for him'
即使人们认为哈尔沙德 · 梅塔是个骗子
‘Even if people thought Harshad Mehta was a liar'
也不在乎
‘they didn't care'
所有投资哈沙德股票的人都获利了
‘All who invested in Harshad's shares, made a profit'
像 ACC、 Polo、马自达这样的公司股价暴涨
‘The way the value of shares like ACC, Polo, Mazda was rising'
没有人能想象得到
‘no one could have imagined it'
哈萨德是新的市场领袖
‘Harshad was the new market guru'
他无处不在
‘He was everywhere'
经纪人、投资者、商人、政客
‘Brokers, investors, businessmen, politicians'
每个男人都想成为哈沙德的特殊男人
‘every man wanted to be Harshad's special man'
每个人都想知道他的下一步计划是什么
‘Everyone wanted to know what his next step would be'
因此，他现在对那些曾经垄断市场的
‘And so, he was now a threat to those brokers and family-owned businesses'
经纪人和家族企业构成了威胁
‘who had monopolized the market so far'
没有人喜欢外人
‘No one likes an outsider'
你整天向上帝祈祷，至少让他晚上睡个好觉
All day you pray to God At least, let him sleep at night
不要说那样的话
Don't say things like that
我想他最近都只回应你的祈祷
I think he only answers your prayers these days
你儿子现在是全国最高级别的纳税人
Your son is now the highest advance taxpayer in the country
甚至比迪鲁拜还要高
Even higher than Dhirubhai
这一定是因为上帝只听你的
This must be because he only listens to you
至少，双手合十拜一次
At least, fold your hands once
这都是因为他的祝福
It's all because of his blessings
妈妈
Mummy
看看你儿子现在能打开多少扇门
Just see, how many doors this Harshad Shantilal Mehta opens
我们的办公室永远不会关门
Our offices will never close
[ Sucheta ]“我发现了哈沙德令人难以置信的一面”
[Sucheta] 'I found out something incredible about Harshad'
真的吗? 你把我带到这个废墟就为了告诉我这个？
Seriously? To tell me that you've brought me to this ruin?
你知道吗，有时候我觉得你在背着我和哈沙德偷情
You know, sometimes it feels that you are cheating on me with Harshad
怎么说? 他是我的第二任妻子吗？
What do they say? Is he my second wife?
才不是，别开玩笑了！
It's not called second wife Stop joking!
不管怎样，你还记得马自达工业吗？
Anyway, you remember Mazda industries?
去年我的第二任妻子收购的公司
Last year, my second wife bought it
抱歉，你继续说
Sorry Go on
- 是的，哈尔沙德去年收购了 -对
- Yes, Harshad bought it last year - Right
这是一家亏损的租赁公司
It was a loss-making leasing company
几个月后，哈尔沙德让这次收购看起来像是一个彻底的转折
and in a few months, Harshad made it seem like it was a complete turnaround
- 是的-股票价格暴涨
- Yeah - The stock prices were shooting
在很短的时间里，就涨到了天花板
through the roof in such a short period of time
抱歉，我在听，继续
Sorry I'm listening Go on
哈萨德在人们心目中树立了一个品牌
Harshad creates a brand in people's mind
他创造了公司的形象
He creates an image of the company
你还记得报纸上的那则广告吗？
Do you remember that advertisement in the newspaper?
“毁灭战士，砰，砰! ”
"Doom, Boom and Zoom!"
这是关于这次收购的转变，彻头彻尾的吹捧文章
It was about this turnaround, complete puff piece
系统地创造了一个马自达的虚假形象
Systematically, a false image of Mazda was created
而马自达现在也将进入房地产和出口业务
And Mazda will now enter the real estate and exports also
他们未来将会研究创新的金融工具
and they will deal with innovative financial instruments
并且将被列入每个主要交易所
And they will be listed in every major exchange
所有这些都是在高摩资本的领导下完成的
All of this under Growmore Corporate
而今年 事实上，这个财年
And this year In fact, this financial year
他们没有通过租赁赚到一分钱
they haven't earned a penny through leasing
我的意思是，从其他收入来看，他们在银行里有519亿卢比
I mean But from other incomes, they have 519 crores in the bank
怎么做到的？
How?
原始股票交易带来的利润，就是这样
Raw profits from stock trading That's how
好极了，听起来不错
Brilliant This sounds great
但你还是没有回答我的问题
But you still haven't answered my question
我们在这里干什么？
What are we doing here?
你可以在任何地方告诉我这些
You could have told me all this anywhere
没错
True
我只是想带你参观一下
I just wanted to give you a tour
这就是马自达工业
This is Mazda Industries
干得漂亮
Good job
- 说真的-谢谢
- Seriously - Thank you
但是你也要知道，他是个顶级玩家
But you also need to understand that he played really well
苏切塔，这是股票市场
Sucheta, it's the stock market
一个赌场
A betting ring
品牌价值就相当于感知
Brand value is equal to perception
没错，但这正是我们需要打破的思维定势
That's true, but that's the very mind-set we need to break
我的意思是 想象一下，有多少人因为这个错误的承诺而买了这只股票？
I mean Imagine, how many people bought this stock because of that false promise?
人们应该知道哈沙德不是天才，他是个骗子
People should know that Harshad is not a genius He is a crook
- 我明白了-除此之外他还犯了一个错误
- I see - And apart from this, he made one more mistake
收购上市公司后，原股东
After taking over listed companies, the original shareholders
给出20% 的公开报价，但他没有答应
are offered an open offer of 20 percent, which he didn't do
我想报道这个故事
And I want to cover this story So that You know
希望这会是个爆炸性新闻
hopefully, it will be breaking news
- 爆炸性新闻?-希望如此
- Breaking news? - Hopefully
那有什么用呢？
What purpose will that serve?
你的爆炸性新闻甚至不会打扰他的睡眠
Your breaking news won't even break his sleep
他现在太高了
He's too big now
这可能不会打断他的睡眠
It might not break his sleep
但即便是能让一些人醒过来
But even if a few people wake up
那也就足够了
it would be good enough
哈尔沙德·梅塔是个骗子
Harshad Mehta is a liar
[ Sucheta ]“是他办公室的一个人”
[Sucheta] 'It was someone else from his office'
他说梅塔先生特意邀请我去见他
'He said Mr Mehta has specially invited me to meet him'
当然，我要走了，毕竟我毁了他的睡眠
'Of course, I'm gonna go After all, I ruined his sleep'
我给你点了酒
I ordered some wine for you
- 给-谢谢
- Here - Thank you
谢谢你
Thank you
那么，回来的感觉如何？
So, how does it feel to be back?
你的第一份工作是在这里，不是吗？
Your first job was here, wasn't it?
你调查过我？
You've researched about me?
你看，无论我做什么都需要可靠的研究支持
You see, whatever I do is backed by solid research
如今，仅仅研究市场是不够的
These days, just studying the market is not enough
谁，什么时候，以及需要多少资金
Who, when and how much is necessary for the market
学习也同样重要
studying that is equally important
那么，根据你的研究，我到底重不重要？
So, according to your study, am I important or not?
这取决于你的方法
That depends on your approach
无论你的方法是建设性的还是破坏性的！
Whether your approach is constructive or destructive!
不管是什么
Whatever it is
我希望自己是个重要的人
I'd like to think that I matter
我很重要
That I'm important
在市场上，只有对我有用的人才重要
In the market, only they are important, who are of use to me
梅塔先生，你
Mr Mehta, you
你做的事，和你做的方式
The things you do, the way you do them
你知道这是不对的，对吧？
you know it's not right, don't you?
“不要害怕放弃好的东西去追求更好的”
"Don't be afraid to give up the good to go for the great"
约翰·戴维森·洛克菲勒
John D Rockefeller
最富有的美国人
The richest American who ever lived
这就是你的财富公式？
That's your formula for the stock market?
我说的不是股票市场
I'm not talking about the stock market
我说的是这个国家
I'm talking about this country
关于这个国家的经济
About the economy of this country
你看，我的想法是
You see, my vision is
加强我们国家的经济
to strengthen the economy of our country
然后继续前进
and take it forward
我需要像你们这样的人来做这件事
And I need people like you in this endeavour
我一个人做不到，对吧？
I can't achieve this alone, can I?
所以
So
你会帮助我建设国家经济还是摧毁它？
will you help me build the economy or will you destroy it?
从股票和基金，你的目标已经转移到议会了吗，梅塔先生？
From shares and stocks, have your dreams shifted to the parliament, Mr Mehta?
这是你的薪水支票，对吗？
This is your salary cheque, right?
你还能做多久？20年？
You have what 20 years of service left?
即使你每年增加20%的收入
Even if you get 20 percent increment every year
你能挣多少钱？
how much will you earn?
加入我吧
Join me
我给你未来
I make people
一千万六百八十万
One crore sixty-eight lakhs
一千九百一十九卢比二十九派萨
one thousand nine hundred nineteen rupees and twenty-nine paise
税前
Before taxation
说得不错
You were right
你给人们未来
You make people
愚弄人们
You make fools of them
梅塔先生，我可以畅所欲言
Mr Mehta, I'm gonna speak very freely
更不用说这个国家了，你甚至没有经营街角商店的远见
Let alone the country, you don't even have the vision to run a corner store
[ Sucheta ]“你可以主宰市场  ”
[Sucheta] 'You can dominate the market'
“直到你的资金来源曝光的那天”
'only till such time that the sources of yours funds are hidden'
一旦这些消息被公之于众
The day those sources become public
你的个人资金撑不过20天
your personal funds won't last for even twenty days
梅塔先生，你不是在建设国家
Mr Mehta, you are not building the nation
你在建设你的财富和形象
You are building your fortune and your image
所以，别再愚弄人们了
So, stop fooling people
你一直都是这个样子吗，还是酒的关系？
Have you always been like this, or is it the wine?
“不管是什么 ”
[Harshad] 'Whatever it is'
很高兴见到你，真的
it was great meeting you Really
我希望能有机会你来采访我
I wish I get a chance to give you an interview
当然
Of course Absolutely
但是在接受我的采访之前，一定要先了解我
But before taking my interview, do get to know me
因为，一旦你了解了我，你就会同意我的观点
Because, once you know me, you will agree with me
谢谢你的酒，梅塔先生
Thank you for the wine, Mr Mehta
但是下一次，不要只看价格下单
But next time, don't just order by price
昂贵并不总是意味着好
Expensive doesn't always mean good
祝你有个愉快的夜晚
You have yourself a good night
等一下，先生，好的
One moment, sir Yeah
- 你好-先生，吉涅什在线上
-[Harshad] 'Hello' - Sir, Jignesh is on the line
他说有急事
He says it's urgent
- 给他接过来-好的，先生
-[Harshad] 'Connect him' - Okay, sir Yeah
是的，吉涅什，怎么了？
Yes, Jignesh What is it?
哈沙德，当心
Harshad Bhai, beware
明天上午8点，所得税局要突袭检查你家和办公室
Tomorrow at 8 am, the income tax will raid your home and offices
已经证实
It is confirmed
那么我会很有风度地欢迎他们
Then I'll welcome them in style
看看谁都会去
Find out who all are going to be there
好吧，保重
[Jignesh] 'Okay, Harshad Bhai'
请出去
Step outside, please
快点
Hurry
发生了什么？
What happened?
所得税部门明天将突袭我们
The income tax department will raid us tomorrow
让孩子们准备好，司机在楼下等着呢
Get the kids ready The driver is waiting downstairs
两分钟
Two minutes
哈尔沙德 · 梅塔
Harshad Mehta
拉马斯瓦米先生，欢迎，请进
Mr Ramaswami, welcome Please come in
怎么了? 你迟到了15分钟
What happened? You are 15 minutes late
你一定是在寺庙附近遇到堵车了
You must've hit some traffic near the temple
人们从早晨开始就开始打扰神
People start bothering God first in the morning
很好
Good
我让他们给你准备早餐了
I've asked them to prepare breakfast for you
我们是素食主义者所以
We are vegetarians so
没有鸡蛋和煎蛋了，对不起
there are no eggs or omelette Sorry
但我要的是南印度早餐
But I have asked for a south Indian breakfast
我希望你没有意见，多萨，乌塔帕姆？
I hope you are okay with upma, dosa, uttapam?
如果有人喜欢古吉拉特小吃的话
And if anyone fancies Gujarati snacks then
厨房就有
chevdo, chakri and ghatia are always there
梅塔先生，我有你家的搜查令
Mr Mehta, I have a search warrant for your house
- 当然-我们要搜查这里
- Of course - We have to search your premise
当然可以，去吧，我已经通知了我的办公室
Sure Go ahead I've even informed my office
孩子们，快点
Come on kids, hurry up
再见，爸爸
Bye, Pappa
嘿，小流氓，过来，再见是什么意思？
Hey, rascals Come here What do you mean ‘bye'?
该怎么迎接客人？
Who will greet the guests?
- 你好，先生-你好，先生
- Greetings, sir - Greetings, sir
去吧
Go now
好了，现在开始吧
[Harshad] 'Now that's an auspicious start'
你可以搜索任何地方，所有东西都在这里
You can search all you want Everything is right here
已经预付了税款
and what isn't, has been already paid in advance tax
开始搜查
Begin the search
房子很大，需要时间，先吃点早餐吧
It's a big house It will take time Have some breakfast first
我们点外卖
We will order it from outside
哦，所以你可以在突袭检查时点外卖？
Oh, so you're allowed to order from outside during an IT raid?
你别动
No
你好
Hello
是的
Yes
是你哥哥
It's your brother
按照规定，这之后你就不能接电话了
As per rules, you can't make any calls after this
我们会接听你所有的电话
And we will receive all your calls
你现在可以说话了
You can speak for now
谢谢，你真是太好了
Thank you You are really kind
你好
Hello
是的，阿什温
Yes, Ashwin
是的，拉马斯瓦米先生和他的团队来了
Yes Mr Ramaswami is here with his team
不，他们不吃早餐
No, they are not having breakfast
不，他们不是在禁食
No, they aren't fasting
不，好吧
No Fine Okay
给你
Here
你要吃薄荷糖吗？
Will you have some after-mint?
- 你还没吃早餐呢-上楼
- You aren't having breakfast - Upstairs
好吧
Okay
来，我们吃吧
[Harshad] 'Here eat peacefully'
你们这些人也请快点把工作做完
You people also, please wrap up your work fast
这里禁止吸烟
Smoking is not allowed here
但是对于政府来说，一切都是允许的
But for the government, everything is allowed
谢谢你
Thank you
先生，我们已经搜查了所有的地方
Sir, we have searched everything
实物记录和文件非常少
[Man1] 'Physical records and files are very few'
他们说所有的东西都保存在电脑里
They say everything is saved in the computers
我们已经没收了电脑，现在送过去
We've confiscated the CPUs and are bringing it
把财务部封锁起来
Seal the Accounts section
好的，先生
Okay, sir
- 这个-你什么意思，封起来？
- This - What do you mean, seal it?
我的办公室有什么问题吗？
What's your problem with my office?
这是调查，梅塔先生
It's an investigation, Mr Mehta
除非我们的调查结束了
Unless we are done
你就不能碰你的账簿
you can't touch your books
这是不允许的
It's not allowed
你知道我的办公室里有多少人吗？
Do you know, how many people work in my office?
我要把他们送到哪里去？
Where will I send them?
因为你，我连办公的地方都没有了
I can't get a new office just because of you
这就是为什么我们没有封锁整个办公室
That's why we aren't sealing the entire office
我们谈完了，收工吧
We are done here Wrap up
把这些都拿走
Take all these
是的
[Man2] 'Yes'
拉马斯瓦米先生，我希望你能尽快找到你要找的东西
I hope you find what you are looking for soon, Mr Ramaswami
你不能让我的办公室关太久
Because you won't be able to keep my office shut for long
说吧，我需要更多细节，他们还发现什么了吗？
Come on I need more details Did they find anything else?
有消息通知我
Keep me posted
什么都没发现
Nothing
肯定有人给他通风报信了
Someone must have tipped him
对
Right
- 下次吧-下次吧
- Next time - Next time